Nicole How

UI/UX Product Designer

I'm a fourth-year design student enrolled in York University's honours bachelor of design program (BDes). My expertise is in UI/UX, but I also cover both digital and print-based media like packaging, and visual design. I value unique perspectives, ambitious goals, and a collaborative approach that promote continual learning. My focus is on designing human-centric and interactive creative solutions one pixel at a time!

\square

how.nicole@hotmail.com



nicole-how.github.io/



behance.net/nicolehow



linkedin.com/in/nicole-how

EXPERIENCE

Office of Vice-President Research & Innovation

Graphic Design & Multimedia Assistant | 09/2023—(Current)

Designed brand-consistent print and digital materials for advertising campaigns, including banners, brochures, and engaging social media posts. Collaborated with manager to develop concepts that complied with creative briefs and brand guidelines. Enhanced service promotion efforts through visually engaging multimedia materials.

REFERENCE // Corey Allen | (upon request)

Open Farm Pet

Graphic Design Internship | 05/2023 - 08/2023

Incorporated company's brand identity into a range of design formats, such as pitch sheets, email correspondence, and printed materials like product packaging. Collaborated with Senior Art Director and Graphic Designers to develop concepts, incorporating feedback to meet creative briefs and brand standards. Compiled and prepared printed presentation materials, ensuring a cohesive representation of the company's visual identity.

REFERENCE // Adam Pittman | Adam@openfarmpet.com

Hack The Woods

Hackathon Winner | 06/2022 - 06/2022

Designed a high-fidelity prototype and devised a compelling pitch to modernize healthcare systems within a strict 24-hour timeframe. Collaborated within multidisciplinary teams, facilitating effective communication and teamwork. Conducted thorough research to identify users, competition, and key issues related to our concept. Generated innovative ideas, developed system requirements, and streamlined task flows. Established a cohesive visual identity and comprehensive design system for the project's unified presentation.

EDUCATION

Honours Bachelor Of Design York University

09/2020 - 04/2024 Awarded Entrance Scholarship

SKILLS

Design Thinking, Wireframing, Prototyping, Interaction Design, User Research & Testing, Task Flows, UI & UX, Information Design, Visual Identity, Typography, Branding

TOOLS

Figma & Figjam, Miro Adobe Suite [XD, Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, Acrobat], HTML, CSS, Javascript, Webflow, Powerpoint, Maya

